A Guide to the Jane Harper papers, 1951-1953
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Jane Harper papers, 1951-1953
The Library of Virginia
50925
.45 cu. ft. and 1 box
Jane Harper
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Crown Collectibles, Chesterfield, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Jane Harper was the daughter of James Griscom Harper (d. 1952) and Ella V. Harper. She graduated from Longwood College. Harper was a member of the Children of the American Revolution.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1951-1953, of Jane Harper (Morris) (1934-2013) of Richmond and Farmville, Virginia, consisting of address books; badges; Children of the American Revolution papers, 1951; clippings; diaries, 1952-1953; greeting cards; letters, 1952-1953, from family and friends; Longwood College papers, 1951-1953; photographs; and other papers concerning her education at Longwood College in Farmville and her social life; as well as her activities in the Society of the Children of the American Revolution.
Letters, 1951-1953, of Jane Harper consist of correspondence from her mother Mrs. James Griscom Harper regarding the family; from classmates and former classmates at Longwood College concerning school activities, as well as their social and love lives; members of the Children of the American Revolution concerning the organization; and from young men who are courting Harper.
Greeting cards, no date, sent to Jane Harper for her birthday, Christmas, and Valentine's Day, as well as general greeting cards.
Diaries, 1952-1953, of Jane Harper containing accounts of her social life, including dates she went on, and accounts of activities with and for the Children of the American Revolution; and address book containing addresses of friends.
Photographs include a color photograph of Jane Harper and a black-and-white photograph of a colonial reenactor. There is also a photograph of Russ Knight included in the correspondence.
Longwood College papers, 1951-1953, include grade reports from 1951 and 1952, information on Longwood College's history and operation, programs for musical shows, and lyrics written in French probably for class.
Children of the American Revolution papers, 1951, contain a program for the annual meeting of the Virginia chapter of the organization, a newsletter, and a pocket New Testament.
Clippings contain articles relating to the Children of the American Revolution and Harper's leadership role in the organization; people and events at Longwood College; and a friend who made a tournament basketball team.
Badges, tickets, cards, and other papers contain name tags from Children of the American Revolution and from events at Longwood College. Also includes a ticket to a play, a napkin, and name cards.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1952 (Folder 1)
- Correspondence, January 1953 (Folder 2)
- Correspondence, February 1953 (Folder 3)
- Correspondence, March 1953 (Folder 4)
- Correspondence, May 1953 (Folder 5)
- Correspondence, June 1953 (Folder 6)
- Correspondence, July 1953 (Folder 7)
- Correspondence, no date (Folder 8)
- Greeting cards (Folder 9)
- Diaries, 1952-1953 (Folder 10)
- Address book (Folder 11)
- Photographs (Folder 12)
- Longwood College grades, 1951-1952 (Folder 13)
- Longwood College, 1951, no date (Folder 14)
- Longwood College musical programs (Folder 15)
- French song lyrics, Longwood College (Folder 16)
- Children of the American Revolution, 1951 (Folder 17)
- New Testament (Children of the American Revolution) (Folder 18)
- Clippings, ca. 1952-1953 (Folder 19)
- Badges, tickets, cards, etc. (Folder 20)